At home, if you're doing one or two loaves and you want to use an old fashioned method, you just have to knead it by hand.
Knead by hand, until you have the window, that's a very good question.
Now, what is a window?
Let me show you what a window is.
A window is when you pack the dough and you stretch it out and the dough becomes so smooth, this is what you call a window.
Where you stretch your dough, until it becomes thin and when you hold it, up to the light, you can see the light come through it, without getting torn and without getting tears in it or without getting holes in it, that's when your dough is ready.
So, at home, when you knead it, you have to knead it enough.
Every so often, take a piece of it, look for your window and if you have your window, your dough is ready.
So that's one way to do it.
As well as mixing the cookie dough and muffin dough, you have to be careful not to over mix anyway.
I don't think, at home, you can really mess it up, by over mixing it.
It's best to watch it and just make sure the ingredients are mixed properly, without being over mixed.
If you over mix it, your cookies will run.
If you over mix your muffin, your muffin will run because what happens is, you will incorporate so much air in it, that the air, in there, will bubble up and make the cookie and the muffin, run.